[
  {
    "name": "Java",
    "questions": [
      {
        "question": "Which component is used to compile, debug and execute the java programs?",
        "options": ["JRE", "JIT", "JDK", "JVM"],
        "answer": "JDK"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which one of the following is not a Java feature?",
        "options": [
          "Object-oriented",
          "Use of pointers",
          "Portable",
          "Dynamic and Extensible"
        ],
        "answer": "Use of pointers"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which environment variable is used to set the java path?",
        "options": ["MAVEN_Path", "JavaPATH", "JAVA", "JAVA_HOME"],
        "answer": "JAVA_HOME"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which exception is thrown when java is out of memory?",
        "options": [
          "MemoryError",
          "OutOfMemoryError",
          "MemoryOutOfBoundsException",
          "MemoryFullException "
        ],
        "answer": "OutOfMemoryError"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of these are selection statements in Java?",
        "options": ["break", "continue", "for()", "if()"],
        "answer": "if()"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of these statements is incorrect about Thread?",
        "options": [
          "start() method is used to begin execution of the thread",
          "run() method is used to begin execution of a thread before start() method in special cases",
          "A thread can be formed by implementing Runnable interface only",
          "A thread can be formed by a class that extends Thread class"
        ],
        "answer": "run() method is used to begin execution of a thread before start() method in special cases"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of these keywords are used for the block to be examined for exceptions?",
        "options": ["check", "throw", "catch", "try"],
        "answer": "try"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of the following is a superclass of every class in Java?",
        "options": ["ArrayList", "Abstract class", "Object class", "String"],
        "answer": "Object class"
      },
      {
        "question": "What is the extension of compiled java classes?",
        "options": [".txt", ".js", ".class", ".java"],
        "answer": ".class"
      },
      {
        "question": "What is Truncation in Java?",
        "options": [
          "Floating-point value assigned to a Floating type",
          "Floating-point value assigned to an integer type",
          "Integer value assigned to floating type",
          "Integer value assigned to floating type"
        ],
        "answer": "Floating-point value assigned to an integer type"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "name": "Operating System",
    "questions": [
      {
        "question": "What is the main function of the command interpreter?",
        "options": [
          "to provide the interface between the API and application program",
          "to handle the files in the operating systemc",
          "to get and execute the next user-specified command",
          "none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "answer": "to get and execute the next user-specified command"
      },
      {
        "question": "CPU scheduling is the basis of ___________",
        "options": [
          "multiprogramming operating systems",
          "larger memory sized systems",
          "multiprocessor systems",
          "none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "answer": "multiprogramming operating systems"
      },
      {
        "question": "If a process fails, most operating system write the error information to a ______",
        "options": [
          "new file",
          "another running process",
          "log file",
          "none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "answer": "log file"
      },
      {
        "question": "In a timeshare operating system, when the time slot assigned to a process is completed, the process switches from the current state to?",
        "options": [
          "Suspended state",
          "Terminated state",
          "Ready state",
          "Blocked state"
        ],
        "answer": "Ready state"
      },
      {
        "question": "A deadlock avoidance algorithm dynamically examines the __________ to ensure that a circular wait condition can never exist.",
        "options": [
          "operating system",
          "resources",
          "system storage state",
          "resource allocation state"
        ],
        "answer": "resource allocation state"
      },
      {
        "question": "For an effective operating system, when to check for deadlock?",
        "options": [
          "every time a resource request is made at fixed time intervals",
          "at fixed time intervals",
          "every time a resource request is made",
          "none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "answer": "every time a resource request is made at fixed time intervals"
      },
      {
        "question": "For real time operating systems, interrupt latency should be ___________",
        "options": [
          "zero",
          "minimal",
          "maximum",
          "dependent on the scheduling"
        ],
        "answer": "minimal"
      },
      {
        "question": "The FCFS algorithm is particularly troublesome for ____________",
        "options": [
          "operating systems",
          "multiprocessor systems",
          "time sharing systems",
          "multiprogramming systems"
        ],
        "answer": "time sharing systems"
      },
      {
        "question": "The portion of the process scheduler in an operating system that dispatches processes is concerned with ____________",
        "options": [
          "assigning ready processes to waiting queue",
          "assigning running processes to blocked queue",
          "assigning ready processes to CPU",
          "all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "answer": "assigning ready processes to CPU"
      },
      {
        "question": "In Unix, which system call creates the new process?",
        "options": ["create", "fork", "new", "none of the mentioned"],
        "answer": "fork"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "name": "DBMS",
    "questions": [
      {
        "question": "Who created the first DBMS?",
        "options": [
          "Edgar Frank Codd",
          "Charles Bachman",
          "Charles Babbage",
          "Sharon B. Codd"
        ],
        "answer": "Charles Bachman"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of the following is not a type of database?",
        "options": ["Hierarchical", " Network", "Distributed", "Decentralized"],
        "answer": "Decentralized"
      },
      {
        "question": "What is information about data called?",
        "options": ["Hyper data", "Tera data", "Meta data", "Relations"],
        "answer": "Meta data"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which SQL command is used to remove a table from a database?",
        "options": ["DELETE", "DROP", "REMOVE", "TRUNCATE"],
        "answer": "DROP"
      },
      {
        "question": "What does ACID stand for in database systems?",
        "options": [
          "Accuracy, Consistency, Isolation, Durability",
          "Atomicity, Consistency, Isolation, Durability",
          "Atomicity, Consistency, Isolation, Dependency",
          "Atomicity, Concurrency, Isolation, Durability"
        ],
        "answer": "Atomicity, Consistency, Isolation, Durability"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which forms have a relation that contains information about a single entity?",
        "options": ["4NF", "5NF", "3NF", "1NF"],
        "answer": "4NF"
      },
      {
        "question": "What does a foreign key combined with a primary key create?",
        "options": [
          "Network model between the tables that connect them",
          "Parent-Child relationship between the tables that connects them",
          "One to many relationship between the tables that connects them",
          "All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "answer": "Network model between the tables that connect them"
      },
      {
        "question": "__________ command is used in SQL to issue multiple CREATE TABLE, CREATE VIEW and GRANT statements in a single transaction.",
        "options": [
          "CREATE CLUSTER",
          "CREATE PACKAGE",
          "CREATE SCHEMA",
          "All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "answer": "CREATE SCHEMA"
      },
      {
        "question": "The DBMS acts as an interface between ________________ and ________________ of an enterprise-class system.",
        "options": [
          "Data and the DBMS",
          "Application and SQL",
          "Database application and the database",
          "The user and the software"
        ],
        "answer": "Database application and the database"
      },
      {
        "question": "The query specifying the SQL view is said to be updatable if it meets which of the following conditions?",
        "options": [
          "select clause contains relation attribute names but not have expressions, aggregates, or distinct specification",
          "from clause has 1 relation",
          "query does not have group by or having clause",
          "All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "answer": "All of the mentioned"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "name": "Networking",
    "questions": [
      {
        "question": "Which of the following is an example of Bluetooth?",
        "options": [
          "wide area network",
          "virtual private network",
          "local area network",
          "personal area network"
        ],
        "answer": "personal area network"
      },
      {
        "question": " What is the full form of OSI?",
        "options": [
          "optical service implementation",
          "open service Internet",
          "open system interconnection",
          "operating system interface"
        ],
        "answer": "open system interconnection"
      },
      {
        "question": "When a collection of various computers appears as a single coherent system to its clients, what is this called?",
        "options": [
          "mail system",
          "networking system",
          "computer network",
          "distributed system"
        ],
        "answer": "distributed system"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which protocol is used to send an email?",
        "options": ["HTTP", "FTP", "SMTP", "IMAP"],
        "answer": "SMTP"
      },
      {
        "question": " Which one of the following is not a function of network layer?",
        "options": [
          "congestion control",
          "error control",
          "routing",
          "inter-networking"
        ],
        "answer": "error control"
      },
      {
        "question": " How is a single channel shared by multiple signals in a computer network?",
        "options": [
          "multiplexing ",
          "phase modulation",
          "analog modulation",
          "digital modulation"
        ],
        "answer": "multiplexing"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which layer does the data link layer take packets from and encapsulate them into frames for transmission?",
        "options": [
          "transport layer",
          "application layer",
          " network layer",
          "physical layer"
        ],
        "answer": "network layer"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which topology requires a multipoint connection?",
        "options": ["Ring", "Bus", "Star", "Mesh"],
        "answer": "Bus"
      },
      {
        "question": "What was the name of the first network?",
        "options": ["ASAPNET", "ARPANET", "CNNET", "NSFNET"],
        "answer": "ARPANET"
      },
      {
        "question": "What does the acronym 'IP' stand for in networking?",
        "options": [
          "Internet Protocol",
          "Internet Provider",
          "Internal Program",
          "Interconnected Protocol"
        ],
        "answer": "Internet Protocol"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "name": "Software Engineering",
    "questions": [
      {
        "question": "____________ is a software development activity that is not a part of software processes.",
        "options": ["Validation", "Specification", "Development", "Dependence"],
        "answer": "Dependence"
      },
      {
        "question": "CASE stands for?",
        "options": [
          "Computer-Aided Software Engineering",
          "Control Aided Science and Engineering",
          "Cost Aided System Experiments",
          "None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "answer": "Computer-Aided Software Engineering"
      },
      {
        "question": "Why do bugs and failures occur in software?",
        "options": [
          "Because of Developers",
          "Because of companies",
          "Because of both companies and Developers",
          "none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "answer": "Because of both companies and Developers"
      },
      {
        "question": "The Cleanroom philosophy was proposed by _________",
        "options": ["Linger", "Mills", "Dyer", "All of the mentioned"],
        "answer": "All of the mentioned"
      },
      {
        "question": "Who proposed the spiral model?",
        "options": ["Barry Boehm ", "Pressman", "Royce", "IBM"],
        "answer": "Barry Boehm"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of the following are CASE tools?",
        "options": [
          "Central Repository",
          "Integrated Case Tools",
          "Upper Case Tools",
          " All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "answer": " All of the mentioned"
      },
      {
        "question": "What are agile manifesto principles?",
        "options": [
          "Customer satisfaction",
          "Face-to-face communication within a development team",
          "Changes in requirements are welcome",
          " All of the mentioned "
        ],
        "answer": " All of the mentioned"
      },
      {
        "question": "Agile Software Development is based on which of the following type?",
        "options": [
          "Iterative Development",
          "Incremental Development",
          "Both Incremental and Iterative Development",
          "Linear Development"
        ],
        "answer": "Both Incremental and Iterative Development"
      },
      {
        "question": "__________ is not suitable for accommodating any change?",
        "options": [
          "RAD Model",
          "Waterfall Model",
          "Build & Fix Model",
          "Prototyping Model"
        ],
        "answer": "Waterfall Model"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of the following is a software development methodology?",
        "options": ["Agile", "Binary", "HTTP", "None of the mentioned"],
        "answer": "Agile"
      }
    ]
  }
]
